Jailton Joel Yanes Romero

Address: Calle 49 # 9 – 03 Barranquilla- Colombia Cellphone: (57)3012807360 - (57)3012842735 E-MAIL: jailtonyanesromero@gmail.com Skype: jailton.yanes linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/jailtonyanes/

PROFILE

Systems Engineer, Bilingual with 12 years of experience in the development of IT projects in national and multinational companies in the technology, telecommunications and services sector. With strengths in the analysis, design and development of software in a web environment, in PHP language, management of the laravel framework, experience in HTML5, JavaScript, Jquery, CSS, Databases (Mysql, DB2, Oracle), experience in PL / development. SQL with Mysql and DB2, experience working with AWS, Digital Ocean and OVH (Cloud computing), experience in the creation and consumption of SOAP and REST web services, Linux management (ubunut), Knowledge and application of the SCRUM methodology for assigning tasks in a work team. Skills for teamwork, learning new technologies and assertive communication with all levels of the organization.

WORK EXPERIENCE

MEDRAR SOFTWARE (Software Developer House)

Web Developer 03/2021 - Currently

- Responsible for the Back-end development on Laravel of fan API to integrate different platforms with CARETREE, a medical web application.
- Responsible for assist to scrum meetings in order to report advances of the development process.

ESTRATEGIA Y GESTIÓN (Software Developer House)

Web Developer 04/2020 - 12/2020

- Responsible for the Back-end development on Laravel of fan API to integrate differents platforms with the electronic billing DIAN system.
- Responsible for integrating the API with other systems based on the same purpose.
- Responsible for supporting end users about the interacting with the API consumption.

DISGLOBAL (BlockChain) Caracas-Venezuela

Senior back-end developer 11/2018 – 03/2020

- Responsible for the Design and Back-end Development in laravel of a cryptocurrency exchange in pairs (BTC / LTC), (BTC / DASH), (BTC / ETH), Responsible for the coordination of front-end development (VueJS) of said platform and work in conjunction with the Indian development staff for the exchange buying and selling, accounting and reporting modules of the application.
- Responsible for coordinating the development of the Hy-8583 standard messaging with which the sales devices carry out commercial transactions.
- Responsible for the coordination of the design, development and implementation of a financial application for points of sale of the NEXGO brand of reference N3 and N5.

Achievements

- I built an API in laravel for the Crypto World Exchange KYC module.
- Contributed to the improvement and completion of the design of the Exchange Mysql database.

- I built the data dictionary in laravel to guarantee the navigability in the English and Spanish languages of said platform.
- I lead the development of the Hy-8583 standard messaging construction between the china and caracas team.

METROTEL

IT and technology analyst (12/2014 – 06/2018)

Responsible for the proper functioning of the company's website developed in PHP and Jquery, serving the requests of internal users (200) and external (20000). Technical leader of the web cootizer projects under jquery, easy payment, METROTEL mobile app, My web account and the Browsealoud component that allows people with visual disabilities to see the content of the site, responsible for the creation of back-end components at the PL / SQL development level in DB2 that served as inputs for the web services of the website and other applications for strategic allies.

Achievements

- I reduced by 80% the waiting time of clients when making any modification to the internet, telephone and television services offered by METROTEL, creating a space on the website to carry out their procedures automatically without the need to move to a service point or call the company's call center (service transfer, line number change, internet speed increase, invoice payment, duplicate download, Wi-Fi password change, line restrictions, schedule technical service line and change of correspondence address).
- I reduced stationery costs by 20% by developing a solution in ZPL language, avoiding the need to buy toner or ink due to the change from laser printer to thermal printer.
- I eliminated the workload in the operations area by 50% by automating the processes that were carried out at the time of processing customer requests.
- I developed a web quote where users can consult the value of the services (Internet, Television and telephone) either individually, duo or trio.
- I coordinated the development of the back-end for the METROTEL mobile app.

ESTRATEGIA Y GESTIÓN (Software Developer House)

Web Developer 06/2011 - 11/2014

- Responsible for the development of the Back-end and Fornt-end in PHP, Mysql and Jquery of a web application to control the process of importing merchandise, controlling the collection of money, storage in the warehouse and final delivery to the client.
- Responsible For leading the design, development and implementation of a web application in php and mysql in the Atlantic transit, called "Virtual course for traffic rule violators".
- Responsible for the creation of a web application in php and oracle of the job performance evaluation type where the performance of the employees who make a career in the institution is measured.
- Responsible for the development of a web application in php mysql and jquery for the creation and assignment of surveillance shifts for the different private security companies.

UNIVERSIDAD DEL NORTE (Barranquilla-Colombia)

Web Developer 04/2010 - 12/2010 (Freelance)

 Responsible for the development of the Back-end and Fornt-end in Php, Mysql and Javascript of a knowledge management portal (PKM) for the COTECMAR shipyard (Bolivar) where users can and share on their intranet, the memories of the good practices of the processes carried out within the company.

EDUCATION

SYSTEMS ENGINEER

Universidad del Norte Graduated

2010

ENGLISH

Universidad del Norte Terminated Course 2009

SKILLS

SCRUM,CSS, HTML5, Javascript, Bootstrap, Jquery,Ajax, GIT, Laravel, Db2, Mysql, PHP, WEBSERVICES,ADVANCED ENGLISH,Cloud Computing